The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: One of the cutest little data structures
教授：最可爱的小数据结构之一
that was ever invented is called the heap.
曾经被发明的被称为堆。
And we're going to use the heap as an example
我们将以堆为例
implementation of a priority queue.
执行优先级队列。
And we'll also use heaps to build a sorting algorithm,
而且我们还将使用堆来构建排序算法，
called heap sort, that is very, very
叫做堆排序
different from either insertion sort or merge sort.
与插入排序或合并排序不同。
And it has some nice properties that neither insertions sort
而且它具有一些不错的属性，两个插入都不排序
nor merge sort have.
也没有合并排序。
But what I want to do is get started
但是我要开始做
with motivating the heap data structure,
通过激励堆数据结构，
regardless of whether you're interested in sorting or not.
无论您是否对排序感兴趣。
So the notion of a priority queue, I think,
因此，我认为优先队列的概念
makes intuitive sense to all of you.
对所有人都很直观。
It's essentially a structure that
本质上是一个结构
implements a set S of elements.
实现元素S的集合。
And each of these elements is associated with the key.
这些元素中的每一个都与密钥相关联。
And as you can imagine, a priority queue is something
可以想象，优先级队列是
where you queue up for something,
在哪里排队
you want to buy something, you want to sell something.
你想买东西，你想卖东西。
You have certain priorities assigned to you,
您分配了某些优先级，
and you want to pick the maximum priority or the min priority.
并且您要选择最大优先级或最小优先级。
You want to be able to delete it from the queue.
您希望能够将其从队列中删除。
You want to be able to insert things into this queue.
您希望能够将东西插入此队列。
You want to be able to change priorities in the queue.
您希望能够更改队列中的优先级。
So all of these operations are interesting operations
所以所有这些操作都是有趣的操作
that should run fast, and for some definition of fast.
应该可以快速运行，并且可以快速定义。
Obviously we are interested in the asymptotic complexity
显然，我们对渐进复杂性感兴趣
definition of fast.
快速的定义。
In that case, we'll be saying does this operation run
在这种情况下，我们将说此操作是否运行
an order n time, order log n time, et cetera.
n次订单，n次订单日志等。
So in general, I think for the next few lectures,
所以总的来说，我认为在接下来的几讲中
you're going to see a specification of data structure
您将看到数据结构的规范
in terms of the operations that the data structure should
就数据结构应执行的操作而言
perform.
表演。
And those of you who have taken six double O five,
你们那些拿了六双O 5的人，
you'll see that it's basically an abstract data type that's
您会发现它基本上是一种抽象的数据类型
associated with these operations.
与这些操作相关联。
So it's a spec for the abstract data type.
因此，它是抽象数据类型的规范。
In six double O five, you had really
在六双O五中，
spent a lot of time on asymptotic complexity,
在渐进复杂度上花了很多时间，
or the efficiency of operations on the abstract data type.
或对抽象数据类型进行操作的效率。
Here, in double O six, you'll specify this ADT,
在此，请在双O六中指定此ADT，
and specify the set of operations or methods
并指定一组操作或方法
in the ADT.
在ADT中。
And we'll talk about whether these are order end complexity
我们将讨论这些是否是订单结束的复杂性
log end complexity, and compare and contrast different ADTs.
记录最终复杂性，并比较和对比不同的ADT。
So today's ADT is a heap.
因此，今天的ADT是一大堆。
And what is the set of operations
什么是操作集
that we'd like to perform on a priority queue?
我们想在优先级队列上执行？
So we can use that to motivate the development of the heap.
因此，我们可以使用它来激发堆的开发。
And those are, insert s x.
然后插入s x。
So you have a set of elements s, and you
所以你有一组元素s
want to be able to insert element x into set s.
希望能够将元素x插入set。
You want to be able to do max of s, which
您希望能够做最大s，这
is return the element of s with the largest key.
返回具有最大键的s的元素。
And different from max of s is extract
与s的最大值不同的是提取
max of x, which not only returns the element with the largest
x的最大值，不仅返回最大的元素
key, but also removes it from s.
键，但也将其从中删除。
So you have a queue, and the person in the queue
所以你有一个队列，队列中的人
was serviced, or the element in the queue was serviced,
已被服务，或队列中的元素已被服务，
and then removed from the queue.
然后从队列中删除。
And finally you can imagine changing
最后你可以想象改变
the priority of a particular element x in the set s.
集合s中特定元素x的优先级。
And this priority, there's an associated key
而这个优先级，有一个关联的密钥
as we have up there with each element.
因为我们每个元素都在那里。
And that key is called a k.
该键称为k。
And increase key s x k would increase the value of x's key
并且增加密钥sxk会增加x的密钥的值
to the new value k.
到新值k。
And k could correspond to, it's just called increase.
k可以对应，这就是所谓的增加。
Most of the time, you're increasing the value
大多数时候，您在增加价值
in maybe a particular application.
在特定的应用中
You could have suddenly a decrease key,
您可能突然有一个减小键，
and you would have to know what the previous value was.
并且您将必须知道以前的值是什么。
And is just a matter of exactly what
而仅仅是什么问题
operation you want to perform.
您要执行的操作。
You could call it update, or increment, whatever you like.
您可以根据需要将其称为更新或增量。
I'm going to spend most of the time here talking
我会花大部分时间在这里聊天
about how you maintain a rep invariant of this data
关于如何维护此数据的表示不变式
structure called the heap, that allows you to do
称为堆的结构，使您可以
these operations in an efficient way.
这些操作都是有效的方式。
And we'll talk about what the efficiency is,
我们将讨论效率是什么，
and we'll try to analyze the efficiency of these algorithms
我们将尝试分析这些算法的效率
that we put up.
我们提出来的
So let's talk about a heap.
因此，让我们谈谈一个堆。
A heap is an implementation of a priority queue.
堆是优先级队列的实现。
It's amazingly and array structure,
数组结构令人惊讶
except that you're visualizing this array
除了您正在可视化此数组
as a nearly complete binary tree.
作为几乎完整的二叉树。
And what does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
Well, the best way to understand that
好吧，了解这一点的最好方法
is by looking at an example.
是通过看一个例子。
We got 10 here, so.
我们这里有10个。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10
So here's my array of 10 elements.
这是我的10个元素的数组。
And the elements are 16, 14, 10, 8, 7.
元素是16、14、10、8、7。
So some set of elements that are in random order,
因此，某些元素以随机顺序排列，
clearly not sorted, and I'm looking at the indices,
显然没有排序，我正在查看索引，
and I'm looking at the elements.
我正在看元素。
I'm going to visualize this as a nearly complete binary tree.
我将其可视化为几乎完整的二叉树。
Is not a full binary tree, because I only
不是完整的二叉树，因为我只
have 10 elements in it, and it would
里面有10个元素，
have to have 15 elements to be a complete binary tree.
必须具有15个元素才能成为完整的二叉树。
And we want to be able to do the general case of an arbitrary
我们希望能够做一个任意的一般情况
size array, and so that's why we have nearly complete here.
大小数组，这就是我们在这里几乎完成的原因。
So what does it mean to visualize this as a tree?
那么将其可视化为树意味着什么？
Well, index one is the root of the tree,
好吧，索引一是树的根，
and that item is the value is 16.
该项目的值为16。
And what I have are indices 2 and 3 are the children,
我的索引是2和3是孩子，
and 4, 5, 6, and 7 are the children of 2 and 3.
和4、5、6和7是2和3的孩子。
And 8, 9, and 10 are the children of 4 and 5,
8、9和10是4和5的孩子
in this case.
在这种情况下。
And so that's the picture you want
这就是你想要的照片
to keep in your head for the rest of this lecture.
在本讲座的其余部分中保持头脑清醒。
Any time you see an array, and you
每当你看到一个数组，你
say we're going to be looking at the heap
说我们要看堆
representation of the array, the picture on the right
数组的表示形式，右侧的图片
tells you what the heap looks like.
告诉您堆的外观。
And so that I'm not going to fill in all of these.
因此，我将不填写所有这些内容。
You can, but I'll do a couple.
您可以，但我会做几个。
So you have 10 here, and 8, 7, et cetera.
所以这里有10个，还有8个，7个等等。
So that's a heap structure.
这就是一个堆结构。
So what's nice about this heap structure,
那么这个堆结构有什么好处，
is that you'll have tree representation of an array,
是您将拥有数组的树表示形式，
and that lets you do a bunch of interesting things.
这样您就可以做很多有趣的事情。
What do you get out of this visualization?
您从这种可视化中得到什么？
Well, the root of the tree is the first element
好吧，树的根是第一个元素
corresponding to i equals 1.
对应于i等于1。
The parent of i is i over 2.
我的父母是我2岁以上。
The left child of i is 2i.
i的左孩子是2i。
And the right child of i is 2i plus 1.
我的右子是2i加1。
So that's essentially what this mapping corresponds to.
因此，这基本上就是该映射所对应的。
Now on top of that, this is just what a heap corresponds to.
现在最重要的是，这就是堆所对应的。
We're going to have particular types of heaps
我们将要使用特定类型的堆
that we'll call max-heaps and min-heaps.
我们将其称为max-heaps和min-heaps。
And as you can imagine, max-heaps and min-heaps
可以想象，最大堆和最小堆
have additional properties on top of the basic
在基本功能之上还有其他属性
keep structures.
保持结构。
So this is essentially a definition of a heap.
因此，这本质上是堆的定义。
Now I'm going to define what the max-heap property is.
现在，我将定义什么是max-heap属性。
And the max-heap property says that the key of a node
而max-heap属性表示节点的密钥
is greater than or equal to the keys of its children.
大于或等于其子项的键。
OK, that's it.
好，就是这样。
It's obviously recursive, in the sense
从某种意义上说，这显然是递归的
that you have to have this true for every node in the tree.
您必须对树中的每个节点都具有此true。
And when you get down to the leaves of the tree,
当你下到树上的叶子时，
they're not children corresponding to the leaves,
他们不是叶子的孩子
So that's a trivial property.
这是一个琐碎的属性。
But at higher levels, you're going to have children,
但更高层次上，您将要有孩子，
and you have to check that.
而你必须检查一下。
So if you look at this example here,
因此，如果您在此处查看此示例，
maybe I should fill this whole thing out.
也许我应该把这件事填满。
A have eight and seven here, and six would be nine.
一个在这里有八个和七个，六个将是九个。
And I have three over here, and then two, four, one.
我这里有三个，然后是两个，四个，一个。
So we can look at this and check whether it
所以我们可以看一下并检查是否
has the max-heap property or not.
是否具有max-heap属性。
Does it have the max-heap property?
它具有max-heap属性吗？
This heap?
这个堆吗
Yeah.
是的
All you have to do is look at these nodes.
您要做的就是查看这些节点。
one, two, three indices, index four, five, six, but you
一，二，三索引，四，五，六索引，但是你
don't have to look at six and seven,
不必看六点和七点
because they don't have any children.
因为他们没有孩子。
But you could shop with five here,
但是你可以在这里买五个
and you look at the children, and there you go.
然后你看着孩子们，然后你就去了。
To the parent is greater than or equal to either
给父母大于或等于
of its children, or its only child, in the case of node
如果是节点，则其子节点或唯一子节点的
five.
五。
And so you have the max-heap property.
因此，您具有max-heap属性。
So fairly straightforward property.
如此简单明了的属性。
And you can imagine defining the min-heap property
您可以想象定义min-heap属性
in an equivalent way.
以等效的方式。
Just replace the greater than or equal to,
只需替换大于或等于，
with less than or equal to.
小于或等于。
So right off the bat, what operation
所以马上开始，什么操作
is going to be trivially performed on a max-heap?
将在最大堆上轻松执行？
This is kind of trivial question.
这是一个琐碎的问题。
Yep.
是的
Just finding the biggest element.
只是找到最大的要素。
Exactly right.
非常正确。
The max operation.
最大操作。
Now, what about extract max?
现在，最大提取量呢？
Is that trivially performed on a max-heap?
这是在最大堆上完成的吗？
No.
没有。
What do I mean by that?
那是什么意思
When you say, max is trivially performed,
当您说时，max是微不足道的，
what it means is that you can return the max,
这意味着您可以返回最大值，
you can find the maximum element, or a maximum element,
您可以找到最大元素或最大元素，
and you obviously don't modify the heap.
而且您显然不修改堆。
And the heap stays the same, so it stays a max-heap.
并且堆保持不变，因此保持最大堆。
In general, when we talk about data structures,
一般来说，当我们谈论数据结构时，
and this goes back to rep invariance, which
这可以追溯到代表不变性
I've mentioned already, you typically
我已经提到过，你通常
want to maintain this rep invariant.
想要保持这个代表不变。
And so the rep invariant of our data structure, in this case,
因此，在这种情况下，我们数据结构的rep不变量
is a max-heap property.
是最大堆属性。
OK.
好。
So we want to maintain the max-heap property
所以我们要保持max-heap属性
as we modify the heat.
当我们修改热量。
So if you go from one heap to another,
因此，如果您从一个堆移到另一个堆，
you start at the max-heap, you want to end with the max-heap.
您从最大堆开始，想要以最大堆结束。
It makes perfect sense, because in one of the simplest
这是完全合理的，因为在最简单的方法之一中
things that you want to do in a priority queue,
您要在优先级队列中要做的事情，
is you want to be able to create a priority queue,
您是否希望能够创建优先级队列，
and you want to be able to run extract max on the priority
并且您希望能够在优先级上运行extract max
queue, over and over.
排队，一遍又一遍。
And what that means, is that you take the max element, you
这意味着，您采用max元素，
delete it, take the next max element, delete it,
删除它，取下一个max元素，删除它，
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
And there you go.
然后你去。
It's a bit of a preview here, but you
这里有点预览，但是你
could imagine that if you did that, you would
可以想象，如果您这样做，您会
get a sorted list of elements in decreasing order.
以降序获得元素的排序列表。
So you see the connection to sorting,
这样您就可以看到排序的关联，
because you could imagine that once we have this heap
因为你可以想象一旦我们有了这个堆
structure, and we can maintain the max-heap property,
结构，我们可以保持max-heap属性，
that we could continually run extract max on it.
这样我们就可以继续对其运行extract max。
And if you could build extract max in an efficient way,
而且，如果您可以高效地构建Extract Max，
you might have a fantastic sorting algorithm.
您可能有一个很棒的排序算法。
So, the big question that really remains,
因此，真正的大问题仍然存在，
is how do we maintain the max-heap property
是如何维护max-heap属性
as we modify the heap?
当我们修改堆？
And the other question, which I haven't answered
还有另一个问题，我没有回答
is-- this array that turns out it was a max-heap,
是-这个数组证明是最大堆，
but it's quite possible that I have
但是我很有可能
a trivial example of an array.
一个简单的数组示例。
In fact, let me make this one.
实际上，让我做这个。
That is not a max-heap.
那不是最大的堆。
It's not a max-heap, it's not a min-heap, it's neither.
这不是最大堆，也不是最小堆，也不是。
Right? it's just a heap.
对？这只是一堆。
So if I just transform, or visualize
因此，如果我只是变换或可视化
I should say, this array as a heap, I don't have a max-heap,
我应该说，这个数组是堆，我没有最大堆，
I don't have a min-heap.
我没有最小的堆。
So if I'm very interested in sorting, and I am,
因此，如果我对排序非常感兴趣，而我
there's this another thing that's
还有另一件事是
sort of missing here that we have to work on,
我们必须努力解决的问题，
which is how are we going to build a max-heap out
我们将如何建立最大堆
of an initially unsorted array.
最初未排序的数组。
Which may or may not turn into a max-heap.
可能会或可能不会变成最大堆。
This trivially happened to be exactly the right thing,
这琐碎恰好是正确的事情，
because I picked it, and it turned into a max-heap
因为我选了它，然后变成了最大堆
just by visualizing it.
只是通过可视化它。
But it's quite possible that you have
但是你很有可能
arrays that are input to your sorting algorithm that
输入到您的排序算法的数组
look like that.
看起来像那样。
OK, so let's dive into heap operations.
好的，让我们深入研究堆操作。
I'm going to have spend some time describing to you
我将花一些时间向您描述
a bunch of different methods that you would call on a heap.
一堆您将在堆上调用的不同方法。
And all of these methods are going
所有这些方法都在
to have to maintain our representation
必须保持我们的代表性
invariant of the max-heap property.
max-heap属性的不变量。
So what are the heap operations that we
那么我们要做的堆操作是什么
have to implement and analyze the complexity for?
必须实施和分析复杂性？
Well, we're going to have build-max-heap
好吧，我们将要建立build-max-heap
which produces a max-heap from an arbitrary or unordered
从任意或无序产生最大堆
array.
数组。
So somehow I got to turn this into, for example,
因此，我必须以某种方式将其转化为
four, two, one.
四，二，一
Which is in effect, sorting this array.
实际上，对这个数组进行排序。
Or changing the order.
或更改顺序。
Maybe not fully sorting it, but changing the order.
可能没有完全排序，而是更改了顺序。
So that's what I have to do, and build-max-heap
这就是我要做的，并且建立最大堆
is going to have to do that.
将必须这样做。
In order to do build-max-heap, the first procedure
为了做build-max-heap，第一步
that I'm going to describe to you, is called max-heapify.
我要向您描述的称为max-heapify。
Heapify.
堆肥。
Sounds a little strange, but I guess
听起来有些奇怪，但我猜
you can -ify pretty much anything.
您几乎可以使任何东西变身。
So you correct a single violation
因此，您可以纠正一个违规情况
of the heap property in a subtree, a subtree's root.
子树（子树的根）中的heap属性。
And I'll explain what I mean by that in just a minute.
我将在一分钟内解释我的意思。
So max-heapify is the fundamental operation
所以最大堆是最基本的操作
that we have to understand here.
我们必须在这里理解。
And we're going to use it over and over.
我们将一遍又一遍地使用它。
What it does, is take something that
它所做的就是拿一些东西
is not a heap, not a max-heap.
不是堆，也不是最大堆。
When I say not a heap from now on,
当我说从现在开始不再是一堆东西时，
pretend that I'm saying not a max-heap.
假装我不是在说最大堆。
We're only going to be talking about max-heaps
我们只会谈论最大堆
for the rest of this lecture.
在本讲座的其余部分。
What max-heapify does, is take something
max-heapify要做的是采取一些措施
that is not quite a max-heap.
那不是最大的堆。
It can't take anything arbitrary.
它不能随心所欲。
It's going to take something where there's
需要采取一些措施
a single violation of the max-heap property
一次违反了max-heap属性
at some subtree of this heap that is given to you,
在给你的这个堆的某个子树上，
and there's a single violation of that.
而且有一个违规行为。
And it's going to fix that.
它将解决此问题。
And we need to be able to do this recursively
我们需要能够递归地执行此操作
at different levels to go build a max-heap
在不同的级别去建立最大堆
from an unordered array.
来自无序数组。
Then once you have that, you can do
然后，一旦有了，就可以做
all sorts of things like insert and extract max, and heap sort,
各种各样的事情，例如插入和提取最大值，以及堆排序，
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So let's take a look at max-heapify using an example.
因此，让我们使用一个示例来看看max-heapify。
I'm not going to write pseudocode for max-heapify.
我不会为max-heapify编写伪代码。
I'll run through an example, and the pseudocode is in the notes.
我将通过一个示例进行演示，并且伪代码在注释中。
The big assumption, and you think
大的假设，你认为
of this as a precondition, for running max-heapify,
这是运行max-heapify的前提，
is the trees rooted at left i and right i are max-heaps.
是根植于左侧i和右侧i的树是最大堆。
So max-heapify is going to look like a comma i.
因此，max-heapify看起来像一个逗号。
a is simply the array, and i is the index.
a只是数组，而i是索引。
Max-heapify is willing to, you're
Max-heapify愿意，您
allowed to crash and not do anything useful
允许崩溃而没有做任何有用的事情
if this precondition is violated in max-heapify.
如果在max-heapify中违反了此前提条件。
But if the precondition is true, then what you have to do
但是如果前提是正确的，那么您必须要做的是
is, you have to return a max-heap correcting
是，您必须返回最大堆校正
this violation.
这种侵犯。
That's the contract.
那是合同。
So let's take a look at an example.
因此，让我们看一个例子。
I think what I want to do is start over here.
我想我想做的就是从这里开始。
I want you to see all of the steps here.
我希望您在这里看到所有步骤。
So we'll take a simple example, and we'll
因此，我们将举一个简单的例子，
run through max-heapify.
通过最大堆运行。
And let's take a look at 16, four--
让我们来看看16
I'm just going to draw the indices for this first example,
我将为第一个示例绘制索引，
and then I won't bother.
然后我就不会打扰
So there you go.
所以你去了。
Is this a max-heap?
这是最大堆吗？
No.
没有。
Because right here, I've got a problem.
因为在这里，我遇到了问题。
4 is less than 14, therefore I have a violation.
4小于14，因此我违反了。
And so, if you look at the call max-heapify A comma 2,
因此，如果您查看呼叫max-heapify A逗号2，
this is an index 2, and all you have to do
这是索引2，您需要做的所有事情
is to look at this subtree.
是看这个子树。
And what you need to be satisfied in order
而您需要满足的条件
to run max-heapify, is that the subtrees of nodes index two,
要运行max-heapify，是节点的子树索引为2，
which is this four node, are max-heaps.
这是这四个节点，是最大堆。
And if you go look below, you see that this is a max-heap
如果您去下面看，您会发现这是一个最大堆
and that's a max-heap.
那是最大的堆。
Most of the time, by the way, you
顺便说一句，大多数时候
will be sort of working bottom up,
将自下而上地工作，
and that's why this is going to make sense.
这就是为什么这很有意义。
This will all work out, because leaves
一切都会解决，因为离开
are by definition max-heaps.
根据定义是最大堆。
Because you don't have to check anything.
因为您不必检查任何东西。
When you put two leaves together,
当你把两片叶子放在一起时
and you want to create a tree like that, or a heap like that,
而您想要创建像这样的树或像这样的堆，
then you run max-heapify.
然后运行max-heapify。
And then when you have a couple different max-heaps,
然后，当您有几个不同的最大堆时，
and you want to put them together
你想把它们放在一起
to make it a bigger max-heap, you'd have run max-heapify.
为了使其更大，可以运行max-heapify。
So that's the way it's going to work.
这就是它的工作方式。
So you want to do a max-heapify A comma 2.
所以你想做一个最大堆的逗号2。
One of the things that's going to be important,
一件很重要的事情，
not in this example, but when we get to sorting,
不是在此示例中，而是在进行排序时，
is that we want to know what the size of the heap is.
是我们想知道堆的大小。
And in this case, the heap size is 10.
在这种情况下，堆大小为10。
So, what does max-heapify do?
那么，max-heapify有什么作用？
Well, all max-heapify does is exchanges elements.
好吧，max-heapify所做的只是交换元素。
And so, if you looked at the code for max-heapify,
因此，如果您查看max-heapify的代码，
and you walked through it, this is what it would do.
然后您浏览了它，这就是它的作用。
You're going to look at 4 and 14,
您将要看4和14
and it's going to say, OK, I'm going
会说，好的，我要
to look at both my children.
看我两个孩子
And I'm going to go ahead and exchange with the bigger child.
我将继续与大孩子交流。
So I'm going to exchange AA[2] with AA[4].
因此，我要与AA [4]交换AA [2]。
And what that would do is, take this, make this 4,
然后要做的就是把这个变成4
and make this 14.
并制作这个14。
And that would be step one.
那将是第一步。
And then when you get to this point,
然后到了这一点，
recursively, you'd realize that the max-heap property
递归地，您将意识到max-heap属性
at this level is violated.
在这个级别被违反。
And so you would go ahead and call max-heapify A comma 4.
因此，您将继续调用max-heapify A逗号4。
And when that happens, that call happens,
当那件事发生的时候，那个电话就发生了，
you're going to look at the two children corresponding
您将要查看对应的两个孩子
to this little subtree there, and you're
到那里的这个小子树，你
going to do the exchange.
去做交流。
You're going to have 8 here and 4 here.
您将在这里有8个，在这里有4个。
So you would exchange AA[4] with AA[8].
因此，您可以将AA [4]与AA [8]交换。
And now you're done, so there's no more calls.
现在您已经完成了，因此不再有通话。
So, fairly straightforward.
因此，相当简单。
It's actually not any more complicated than this.
实际上，没有比这更复杂的了。
There may be many steps.
可能有很多步骤。
What might happen is that you'd have to go all the way down
可能会发生的是，您必须一直走下去
to the leaves.
到树叶。
And in this case, you went a couple of steps,
在这种情况下，您走了几步，
and then you got to stop.
然后你必须停下来。
But obviously, you could have a large heap,
但显然，您可能会有一大堆，
and it could take a bunch of time.
这可能会花费很多时间。
So, what is the complexity of max-heapify?
那么，max-heapify的复杂性是什么？
Anybody?
有人吗
Yeah.
是的
Back there.
回到那里。
AUDIENCE: Ultimately, potentially,
听众：最终，潜在地，
if the tree is totally upside down,
如果树完全倒挂，
you could potentially switch every node to make it order in.
您可能会切换每个节点来订购它。
PROFESSOR: Every node to make it order in.
教授：将其排序的每个节点。
Everybody, anybody.
每个人，任何人。
Do you have a different answer?
您有其他答案吗？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
听众：登录n。
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
Why is it log n.
为什么登录n。
AUDIENCE: Because I think the worst case scenario,
听众：因为我认为最坏的情况是，
all of your-- the worst case scenario you
您所有-最坏的情况
would have [INAUDIBLE] on the left-hand side,
在左侧会显示[音频不清晰]，
[INAUDIBLE] right-hand side.
[听不清]右侧。
And it would be skewed.
而且它会歪斜。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So you're arguing that the solution
教授：所以您在争论解决方案
to the recurrence gives you a logarithmic complexity.
复发给您带来了对数复杂性。
Alright.
好的。
Not quite.
不完全的。
There's an easier way of arguing this.
有一种更简单的方法可以解决这个问题。
this Yeah.
是的
Back there.
回到那里。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: That's right.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: That's right.
教授：是的。
So what is the complexity?
那么复杂度是多少？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
听众：登录n。
PROFESSOR: Log n.
教授：登录n。
Great.
大。
Excellent.
优秀的。
Definitely worth a cushion.
绝对值得一坐。
Missed you by that much.
非常想念你。
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
听众：谢谢。
PROFESSOR: It's pretty soft, by the way.
教授：顺便说一句，它很柔软。
Right.
对。
OK.
好。
So, if I hit somebody, they get a cushion.
因此，如果我撞到某人，他们会得到缓冲。
OK.
好。
That's exactly right.
没错
Thanks for that description.
感谢您的描述。
So, first off, there's two important aspects
因此，首先，有两个重要方面
to this argument.
这个论点。
The first thing is, that we're visualizing
首先是，我们正在可视化
this is a nearly complete binary tree.
这是几乎完整的二叉树。
It is not an unbalanced tree.
它不是一棵不平衡的树。
Alright?
好的？
We'll talk about unbalanced trees and balanced trees
我们将讨论不平衡树和平衡树
in the next couple of lectures.
在接下来的两节课中。
But the visualization of a heap is a nearly complete binary
但是堆的可视化几乎是完整的二进制文件
tree.
树。
And, in fact, if you had 15 elements,
而且，实际上，如果您有15个元素，
it would be a perfect binary tree.
这将是一个完美的二叉树。
So the good news is, that the height of this visualization
好消息是，这种可视化的高度
tree is bounded by log n.
树以log n为边界。
That's the good news.
那是个好消息。
And you want to exploit that good news
而你想利用这个好消息
by creating algorithms that go level by level.
通过创建逐级执行的算法。
If you can do that, you're going to have logarithmic complexity
如果能做到，那将有对数复杂性
algorithms.
算法。
So that was one aspect of it.
这就是它的一方面。
The other aspect of it, is the key assumption
另一个方面是关键假设
that we're making, with respect to build-max-heap,
关于build-max-heap，我们正在做的
that there was a single violation.
只有一次违规。
It is true that the answer that was given that was order n,
确实，给出的答案是n阶，
would be a problem.
会是个问题。
I could set it up so that's actually the right answer,
我可以进行设置，这样实际上是正确的答案，
if I did not have this assumption-- where
如果我没有这个假设-哪里
do I have that here-- assume that the trees rooted at left i
我在这里有那个吗-假设树根在我的左边
and right i are max-heaps.
对，我是最大堆。
So maybe that's what you were thinking.
所以也许这就是您的想法。
But this is a key assumption.
但这是一个关键的假设。
This is going back and like making
这回去就像
connections between classes.
类之间的连接。
This is a precondition that makes
这是使
the algorithm more efficient.
该算法更加有效。
Makes the implementation easier.
使实施更容易。
And this precondition essentially
前提是
says that you have to just go down and do a number of steps,
说你必须走下去并做一些步骤，
that's the number of levels in the tree, which is logarithmic.
那是树中的级别数，它是对数的。
So that's the story here with the max-heapify.
这就是max-heapify的故事。
It's order log n, in terms of complexity.
就复杂性而言，它是订单日志n。
That's the number of steps that you have.
那就是您要执行的步骤数。
And it's a basic building block for all of the other algorithms
这是所有其他算法的基本构建块
that we look at for the rest of this lecture, and in section
我们将在本讲座的其余部分以及本节中
tomorrow.
明天。
Let's talk about how you would take max-heapify and use
让我们谈谈如何使用max-heapify和使用
it to do build-max-heap.
做build-max-heap。
So the first step now, let's say that we
所以现在第一步，我们说
want to go and get a nice sorting algorithm.
想去获得一个不错的排序算法。
We don't like insertion sort, we don't like merge sort.
我们不喜欢插入排序，我们不喜欢合并排序。
We'd like to get a heap-based sorting algorithm.
我们想要一个基于堆的排序算法。
One of the things that we need to do, as I said,
正如我所说，我们要做的一件事是，
is to take an unordered array, and turn it
是取一个无序数组，然后将其旋转
into a max-heap, which is a non-trivial thing to do.
变成最大堆，这是不平凡的事情。
And once we do that, we can do this extract-max deal
一旦完成，我们就可以进行extract-max处理
to sort the array.
对数组进行排序。
So the first step is, we want to convert an array A 1
所以第一步是，我们要转换数组A 1
through n into a max-heap.
通过n到最大堆。
And the key word here is max-heap,
这里的关键词是最大堆
because every array can be visualized as a heap.
因为每个数组都可以可视化为一个堆。
And I am going write the pseudocode for build-max-heap,
我将为build-max-heap编写伪代码，
because it's just two lines of code.
因为只有两行代码。
And that's about the limit of a size of a program
那就是程序大小的限制
I can really understand, or explain, I should say.
我应该说，我真的可以理解或解释。
And this is what it looks like.
这就是它的样子。
Alright.
好的。
that's it.
而已。
Build-max-heap says go from i equals n, by 2, down to 1.
Build-max-heap说从i等于n乘以2，下降到1。
Max-heapify A of i.
i的最大堆A。
So someone explain to me why I can start with n over 2,
所以有人向我解释了为什么我可以从2开始
and why I'm going down to 1.
以及为什么我下降到1。
Yep.
是的
I saw you first.
我第一次见到你
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Leaves are good.
教授：叶子很好。
Leaves are good.
叶子很好。
I'll let you go on in a second.
我让你继续。
Leaves are good, because if you look at elements A of n over 2,
叶子是好的，因为如果您看n的元素A超过2，
plus 1 through n, are all leaves.
加1到n，都是叶子。
That's a good observation.
这是一个很好的观察。
And this is true for any array.
这对于任何数组都是如此。
It doesn't matter what n is.
n是什么都没关系。
Doesn't have the power of 2, or 2 [INAUDIBLE] minus 1,
没有2的幂或2 [听不清]减1，
or anything like that.
或类似的东西。
And leaves a good, because they automatically
并留下一个好的，因为它们会自动
satisfy the backseat property.
满足后座属性。
Continue.
继续。
AUDIENCE: OK. [INAUDIBLE].
听众：好的。 [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
Beautiful.
美丽。
I won't hit anybody here.
我不会在这里打任何人。
So that's it.
就是这样了。
The reason this works, is because you're
之所以有效，是因为你
calling max-heapify multiple times,
多次调用max-heapify，
but every time you call it, you satisfy the precondition.
但每次调用它，您都满足前提。
And the leaves are automatically max-heaps.
并且叶子自动是最大堆。
Then you start with n over 2.
然后，从n开始于2。
You are going to see two leaves as your children
您将看到两片叶子作为您的孩子
for the n over 2 node, right?
对于n over 2节点，对吗？
I mean, just pick an example here.
我的意思是，在这里仅举一个例子。
Our 2 is an A of 5, right?
我们的2是5的A，对吧？
You're out here.
你在这里
In this case, depending on the value of n,
在这种情况下，取决于n的值，
you may have either two children, or just one child.
您可能有两个孩子，或只有一个孩子。
And you have one child.
你有一个孩子。
But regardless of that, that's going
但是不管怎样，
to be a max-heap, because it's a leaf.
成为最大堆，因为它是一片叶子。
And so you'll have two leaves, and you
这样你就会有两片叶子，而你
need to put them together.
需要将它们放在一起。
And that's a fairly straightforward process
这是一个相当简单的过程
of attaching the leaves together.
将叶子粘在一起的过程。
You might have to do a swap, based on what the element is.
您可能必须根据元素是什么进行交换。
One operation and you get a little small tree,
一次手术，您会得到一棵小树，
that's a max-heap.
那是最大的堆。
And then you do a bunch of other things
然后你做一堆其他的事情
that all work on leaves, because n over 2 minus 1
都在叶子上工作，因为n超过2减1
is probably also going to have leaves
可能还会有叶子
as it's children, given the large value of n.
因为它是孩子，所以n大。
There will be a bunch of things where
会有很多东西
you work on these level one nodes, if you will,
您将在这些一级节点上工作，如果愿意，
that all have leaves as children.
小时候都有叶子。
And then you work on the level two nodes,
然后您在第二层节点上工作，
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
And as I said before, you're working your way up,
正如我之前说的，您正在努力，
and you're only working with max-heaps
而且你只用最大堆
as your left child and your right child.
作为你的左孩子和右孩子。
That make sense?
有道理？
If you do that, and this is a fairly straightforward
如果您这样做的话，这是相当简单的
question, if you do a straightforward
问题，如果你做一个简单的
analysis of this, what is the complexity of build-max-heap?
对此进行分析，build-max-heap的复杂性是什么？
Yep.
是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
So that's order.
这就是命令。
Order n log n.
顺序n日志n。
Now, this is through a simple analysis.
现在，这是通过简单的分析。
Now I'm going to give you a chance
现在我要给你机会
to tell me if you can do better than that.
告诉我是否可以做得更好。
Or not.
或不。
In terms of analysis.
在分析方面。
It's a subtle question.
这是一个微妙的问题。
It's a subtle question, that I'm asking.
我要问的是一个微妙的问题。
I'm saying, this is the algorithm, alright?
我是说，这是算法，好吗？
I don't want you to change the algorithm,
我不要你改变算法
but I want you to change your analysis.
但我希望您更改分析。
The analysis that you just did was,
您刚才所做的分析是
you said, I got [INAUDIBLE] n steps here,
你说过，我在这里[听不清] n步，
because it's n by 2 steps.
因为它是n分2步。
Looks like each of the steps is taking log n time.
看来每个步骤都需要花费n倍的时间。
So that's n log n.
这就是n log n。
And I was careful.
而且我很小心。
I put big O here.
我把大O放在这里。
OK?
好？
Because that's an upper bond.
因为那是一个较高的纽带。
So that's a valid answer.
所以这是一个有效的答案。
Can you do better?
你能做得更好吗？
Can you do a better analysis-- and I'll
您能做一个更好的分析吗，我会
let you go first-- can you do a better analysis that somehow
让您先走-您能以某种方式进行更好的分析吗
gives me better complexity?
给我更好的复杂性？
AUDIENCE: I think you bring it to [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我想你把它带到[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How?
怎么样？
AUDIENCE: So each node get a maximum of two [INAUDIBLE].
听众：因此，每个节点最多获得两个[听不清]。
So, for some n, there will be a constant number of comparisons
因此，对于某些n，将有恒定数量的比较
to max-heapify that [INAUDIBLE].
以最大程度地堆砌[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
It's hard to explain.
很难解释。
You're on the right track.
您走在正确的轨道上。
Absolutely on the right track.
绝对正确。
So it turns out that, and I'll do this,
事实证明，我会这样做，
it's going to take a few minutes here,
这里要花几分钟，
because I write some things out.
因为我写了一些东西。
You have to sum up a bunch of arithmetic series, and so on.
您必须总结一堆算术级数，依此类推。
So it's a bit unfair to have to speak out the answer,
因此，必须大声说出答案有点不公平，
but the correct answer, in fact, is
但事实上，正确的答案是
that this is order n complexity.
这就是n阶复杂度。
This algorithm that I put up here,
我在这里提出的算法
if you do a careful analysis of it,
如果您仔细分析一下
you can get order n out of it.
您可以从中得到订单n。
And we'll do this careful analysis.
我们将进行仔细的分析。
And I'll tell you why it's order n,
我会告诉你为什么要订购n
in terms of a hand wavy argument.
波浪形的争论。
A hand wavy argument is that you're doing basically,
一个波浪形的争论是，你基本上在做，
obviously no work for the leaves.
显然，叶无用。
But you're not even counting that,
但是你甚至都没有数过
because you're starting with n over 2.
因为您要从2以上的n开始。
But when you look at the n over 2 node,
但是当您查看n over 2节点时，
it's essentially one operation, or two operations,
本质上是一个操作或两个操作，
in whichever way you count, to build max-heap.
以您认为的任何一种方式来建立最大堆。
And so for that first level of nodes,
因此，对于第一级节点，
it's exactly one operation.
这只是一项操作。
The first level that are above the leaves.
叶子上方的第一层。
For the next level, you may be doing two operations.
对于下一个级别，您可能要执行两个操作。
And so there is an increase in operations
因此，运营增加了
as you get higher and higher up.
随着你越来越高。
But there are fewer and fewer nodes as you
但是随着您的节点越来越少
at higher and higher up, right?
在越来越高的地方吧？
Because there's only one node that is the highest level node.
因为只有一个节点是最高级别的节点。
The root node.
根节点。
That node has logarithmic number of operations,
该节点具有对数个运算，
but it's only one node.
但这只是一个节点。
The ones down on the bottom have a constant number
底部的数字恒定
of operations.
操作。
So I'll put all of this down, and hopefully you'll
所以我会把所有这些都放下来，希望你会
be convinced by the time we've done some math here,
相信我们在这里做一些数学的时间，
or some arithmetic here, but you can quantify what I just
或一些算术运算，但您可以量化我的
said fairly easily, as long as you're
说的很轻松，只要你
careful about the counting that we have to do.
注意我们必须做的计数。
So this is really, truly counting.
因此，这确实非常重要。
Analysis has a lot to do with counting.
分析与计数有很大关系。
And we're just being more careful with the counting,
而且我们在计数方面更加谨慎，
as opposed to this straightforward argument that
与此简单的论点相反
wasn't particularly careful with the counting.
对计数不是特别小心。
So let's take a look at exactly this algorithm.
因此，让我们来看看这个算法。
And I want to make an observation.
我想观察一下。
Which is what I just did, but I'd like to write it out.
这就是我刚刚做的，但是我想写出来。
Where we say, max-heapify takes constant time
我们说的最大堆花时间是恒定的
for nodes that are one level above leaves.
对于叶子上方一级的节点。
And, in general, order L time for nodes
而且，通常，节点的L时间为
that are L levels above the leaves.
在叶子上方L个水平。
That's observation number one.
这是第一观察结果。
Observation number two is that we
第二个观察是我们
have n over 4 nodes that, give or take one,
在4个以上的节点中有n个，给予或接受一个，
depending on the value of n.
取决于n的值。
I don't want to get hung up on floors and ceilings.
我不想挂在地板和天花板上。
And in any case, we're eventually
无论如何，我们最终
going to get an asymptotic result,
得到渐近结果，
so we don't have to worry about that.
因此我们不必为此担心。
But we have n over four nodes with level one, n over 8
但是我们有n个超过1个节点的四个节点，n个超过8个节点
with level two.
第二级。
And 1 node with log n, sort of the log n
和1个具有日志n的节点，排序为日志n
level, which is the root.
级别，这是根本。
So this is decrease in terms of nodes as the work
所以这是节点工作量的减少
that you're doing increases.
你正在做的事情增加。
And that's the careful accounting that we have to do.
这就是我们必须要做的仔细核算。
And so all I have to do now to prove to you that this
因此，我现在要做的就是向您证明
is actually an order and algorithm,
实际上是一个命令和算法，
is to write a little summation that sums up
是写一些总结
all of the work across these different levels.
这些不同层次上的所有工作。
And so the total amount of work in the 4 loop
这样4个循环中的总工作量
can be summed as n divided by 4, times 1, times c.
可以求和为n除以4乘以1乘以c。
So this sum, I have one level here,
所以这个总和，我在这里有一个层次，
and I'm going to do some constant amount of work
我要做一些固定的工作
for that one level.
对于那个水平。
So I'm just going to put c out there,
所以我要把c放在那里
because eventually I can take away the c, right?
因为最终我可以拿走c，对吧？
That's the beauty of asymptotics.
那就是无症状的美。
So we don't need to argue about how much work
所以我们不需要争论多少工作
is done at that one level, how many swaps,
在那个级别完成了多少次交换
et cetera, et cetera.
等，等等。
But the fact is that these n over four nodes
但是事实是，这n个超过四个节点
are one level above the leaves.
在叶子上方一层。
That's what's key.
那才是关键。
And then I have n over 8 times 2c, plus n over 16 times 3c,
然后我得到n超过8倍2c，再加上n超过16倍3c，
plus 1 times log of n c.
加n乘以1的对数。
I've essentially written in an arithmetic expression
我基本上是用算术表达式写的
exactly what I have observed on the board above.
正是我在上面的板上观察到的。
Stop me if you have questions.
如有疑问，请阻止我。
Now I'm going to set-- just to try and make
现在我要开始设置-只是尝试使
this a little easier to look at, and easy to reason
这看起来更容易理解，而且容易推理
about-- I'm going to set n over 4 to 2 raised to k,
关于-我将把4的n设置为2，将n设置为k，
and I'm going to simplify.
我将简化。
I'm just pulling out certain things,
我只是拿出某些东西
and this thing is going to translate to c times 2
这个东西将转换为c乘以2
raised to k, times 1, divided by 2 raised to 0,
提高到k，乘以1，除以2，得到0，
2 divided by 2 raised to 1, 3 divided by 2 raised to 2,
2除以2升为1，3除以2升为2，
et cetera, k plus 1 divided by 2 raised to k.
等，将k加1除以2得出k。
Now, if that was confusing, raise your hand,
现在，如果这令人困惑，请举手，
but it's essentially identical given the substitution and sort
但是考虑到替换和排序，它基本上是相同的
of just applying the distributive law.
仅适用分配法。
And the reason I did this, is because I
我这样做的原因是因为我
wanted you to see the arithmetic expression that's in here.
希望您看到其中的算术表达式。
Now we do know that 2 raised to k is n over four, of course.
现在我们确实知道，将2升至k等于4上的n。
But if you look at this expression that's inside here,
但是，如果您查看此处的表达式，
what is this expression?
这个表达是什么？
Anyone?
任何人？
Can you bound this expression?
你能约束这个表达吗？
Someone?
有人吗
For the cushion.
为垫子。
Remember your arithmetic series from wherever it was.
无论身在何处，都请记住您的算术级数。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
You know better than I. I guess you took those courses more
你比我了解得更多。我想你选修了那些课程
recently, but what happens with that?
最近，但是那会发生什么呢？
Those of you who have calculators,
那些有计算器的人，
I mean, you could plug that in, and answer that.
我的意思是，您可以插入并回答。
No one?
没有人？
Go ahead.
前进。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
You know that it's going to merge to two.
您知道它将合并为两个。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly what I was looking for.
教授：那正是我想要的。
Essentially, well, it's not quite two, because you have a 1
从本质上讲，它不是两个，因为您有一个1
here, and you have a 1 here, but you're exactly right.
在这里，您这里有1，但您说得很对。
I mean, two is good.
我的意思是，两个很好。
It's asymptotic, I mean, come on.
我的意思是说，这是渐近的。
I'm not going to complain about two versus three, right?
我不会抱怨两个还是三个，对吗？
So the point is it's bounded by a constant.
因此，关键是它以一个常数为界。
It's bounded by a constant.
它以常量为界。
This is a convergent series and it's bounded by a constant.
这是一个收敛的级数，并且以一个常数为界。
And we can argue about what the constant is.
我们可以争论什么是常数。
It's less than three.
不到三个。
And it doesn't matter of k goes to infinity.
与k到无穷大无关。
And you want k to go to infinity,
你想让k达到无穷大，
but it doesn't matter if k is small or k is large,
但是k小还是k都没关系，
this is bounded by a constant.
这是一个常数。
And that's the key observation.
这就是关键的观察。
What do we have left?
我们还剩下什么？
We have a constant there.
我们在那里有一个常数。
We have a c, which is a constant,
我们有一个交流电，这是一个常数，
and we have a 2 raised to k, which is really n.
我们将k的值提高了2，实际上是n。
So there you go.
所以你去了。
There you have your theta n complexity.
那里有您的理论复杂性。
Now I can say theta n, because I know it's theta n.
现在我可以说theta n，因为我知道它是theta n。
But big O of n, theta n, that's what it is.
但是n是theta n的大O就是这样。
So that's what I'd say is subtle analysis.
所以我要说的是微妙的分析。
Clearly a little more complicated than anything
显然比任何事情都要复杂
we've done so far, and let me see if there are questions.
到目前为止，我们已经完成了，让我看看是否有问题。
How many people got this?
有多少人得到这个？
I did too.
我也是
Someone who didn't get it, ask a question.
有人不明白，问一个问题。
What didn't you get?
没得到什么
What step would you like me to repeat here?
您希望我在这里重复什么步骤？
Any particular step?
有什么特别的步骤吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: This thing here?
教授：这东西在这里吗？
Right here?
就在这儿？
OK, so you're not convinced that this expression
好，所以您不相信这个表达
got translated to this expression.
被翻译成这个表达。
So let me try and convince you of that, alright?
因此，让我尝试说服您，好吗？
So let's take a look at each of the terms.
因此，让我们看一下每个术语。
n by 4 is 2 raised to k.
n乘4是2升至k。
I'm just looking at this term and this term.
我只是在看这个学期和这个学期。
n by 4 is 2 raised to k.
n乘4是2升至k。
c is c.
c是c。
And I just wrote 1 as 1 divided by 2 raised to 0, which is 1.
我只写了1为1除以2升为0（即1）。
And the reason I want you to do this,
我希望您这样做的原因，
is because I want to show you an expression where in some sense,
是因为我想向您展示某种意义上的表达，
this is the term that is the summation for your expression.
这是表达的总和。
If we just replace this, you can write this out
如果我们只是替换掉它，你可以写出来
as i equals 0 through k, I plus 1 divided by 2 raised to i.
当我等于0到k时，我加1除以2得出i。
That is the symbolic form of this expression,
那是这个表达的象征形式，
which came from here.
从这里来的
And then the argument was made that this
然后有人争论说
is a convergent series and is bounded by a constant.
是一个收敛的级数，并以一个常数为界。
That make sense?
有道理？
Good.
好。
So that's pretty neat, right?
这很整洁吧？
I mean, you have the same algorithm and, whala,
我的意思是，您有相同的算法，而且，
it suddenly got more efficient.
突然变得更有效率。
Doesn't always happen, but that tells you
并非总是会发生，但这可以告诉您
that you have to have some care in doing
你必须在做的时候多加注意
your analysis, because what really happened here, was you
您的分析，因为这里真正发生的是您
did a rudimentary analysis.
做了初步的分析。
You said, this was order log n, big O log n,
您说，这是订单日志n，大O日志n，
and you said this was theta n, and you ended up with this.
然后您说这是theta n，结果就这样了。
But in reality, it's actually a faster algorithm.
但实际上，它实际上是一种更快的算法。
So that's the good news.
这是个好消息。
Build-max-heap can be done in order n time.
Build-max-heap可以按n次完成。
Now in the time that I have left, it turns out,
事实证明，在我离开的那一刻，
we are essentially all the way to heaps sort.
从本质上讲，我们一直在进行堆排序。
Because all we have to do is use,
因为我们要做的就是使用，
once we have build-max-heap, I'll
一旦有了build-max-heap，我会
just write out the code for heap sort,
只需写出用于堆排序的代码，
and you can take a look at examples in the notes.
您可以在注释中查看示例。
The pseudocode, I should say, for heap sort.
我应该说，用于堆排序的伪代码。
And it looks like this.
它看起来像这样。
The first step that you do is you build max-heap
要做的第一步是构建max-heap
from the unordered array.
来自无序数组。
Then you find the maximum element AA[1].
然后找到最大元素AA [1]。
All of this I've said multiple times.
我已经多次说过所有这些。
Now the key step is, you could do extract max,
现在的关键步骤是，您可以提取最大
but one nice way of handling this,
但是一种很好的处理方式
is to swap the elements AA[n] with AA[1].
将用AA [1]交换元素AA [n]。
Let me write this out and explain
我写出来解释一下
exactly what that means.
确切的意思。
Now the maximum element is at the end of the array.
现在，最大元素位于数组的末尾。
When you do the swap.
进行交换时。
That's the one step that I will have
那是我要做的一步
to spend another minute on.
再花一点时间。
Now we discard node n from the heap,
现在我们从堆中丢弃节点n，
simply by decrementing heap size.
只需通过减少堆大小即可。
So the heap becomes n minus 1 in size
所以堆的大小变成n减1
from n in the first iteration.
在第一次迭代中从n开始。
Now the new root after the swap may violate max-heap,
现在，交换之后的新根目录可能会违反max-heap，
we'll call it the max-heap property,
我们将其称为max-heap属性，
but the children are max-heaps.
但是孩子们堆得最多。
So that's the one node that can possibly violate it.
因此，这是一个可能违反它的节点。
So what that means, is we can run max-heapify to fix this.
因此，这意味着我们可以运行max-heapify来解决此问题。
And that's it .
就是这样。
Once you do that, you go back to that step.
完成此操作后，您将返回到该步骤。
So what's happened here exactly?
那么这里到底发生了什么？
Well this part we spent a bunch of time on.
好吧，这部分我们花了很多时间。
element is the maximum element, so you grab that.
element是最大的元素，因此您可以抓住它。
And you know that's a maximum element.
而且您知道这是最大的要素。
One way of doing it is to use extract max, but rather
一种方法是使用extract max，而是
than doing extract max, which I haven't explained to you,
而不是我没有向您解释的最大提取量，
you could imagine that you go off
你可以想象你会离开
and you swap the top element with the bottom element,
然后将顶部元素与底部元素交换，
and then you discard it.
然后将其丢弃。
So here's a trivial example, where
所以这是一个简单的例子，
let's say I had 4, 2, and 1, which is a max-heap.
假设我有4、2和1，这是最大堆。
What would happen is you'd say, I'm going to take 4
你会说什么，我要拿4
and I'm going swap it with 1.
我将其与1交换。
And so you have, 1, 2, and 4.
这样就得到了1、2和4。
Now four used to be AA[1], and that's the maximum element,
现在四个曾经是AA [1]，这是最大的元素，
and I'm just going to delete it from the heap,
我将要从堆中删除它，
which means I'm going to end up with a heap that looks like--
这意味着我将要得到一个看起来像是的堆
a heap, not a max-heap-- that looks like this.
这样的堆，而不是最大堆。
And I write down 4 here.
我在这里写下4。
4 is the first element in my sorted array.
4是我排序数组中的第一个元素。
Now I look at 1 and 2, and 1 and 2 there's
现在我看1和2，还有1和2
obviously not a max-heap.
显然不是最大堆。
But I can run max-- I know the child is a max-heap,
但是我可以最大跑-我知道孩子是最大堆
so I can run max-heapify on this.
所以我可以在此上运行max-heapify。
And what this turns into is 2 and 1.
变成2和1。
And at this point, I know that the max is the root,
至此，我知道最大值是根，
because I've run max-heapify and I take 2 out,
因为我已经跑了max-heapify，我拿了2个，
and after this, it becomes trivial.
之后，它变得微不足道了。
But that's the general algorithm.
但这是通用算法。
So this whole thing takes order n log n time,
因此，这整个过程需要n log n次的时间，
because even though build-max-heap
因为即使build-max-heap
is order n and max element is constant time,
是n阶，最大元素是恒定时间，
swapping the elements is constant time.
交换元素是恒定的时间。
But running max-heapify is order log n time,
但是，运行max-heapify是订单登录时间n，
and you have n steps.
并且您有n个步骤。
So you have an order n log n algorithm.
因此，您有一个阶数为n log n的算法。
But the first step was order n, which
但是第一步是阶n
is what we spent a bunch of time on.
我们花了很多时间。
So I'll show you examples in the notes,
因此，我将在笔记中为您展示示例，
and that will get covered again in section.
这将在本节中再次讨论。
I'll stick around for questions.
我会四处询问。
See you next time.
下次见。